MIGUEL A. URRUTIA GLOBAL IT DIRECTOR



PROFILE STATEMENT

Highly qualified and results-driven Global IT Director with over 12 years of experience. Proficient at attaining company strategic goals and objectives relevant to network design, information technology, security best practices, and leading technically skilled personnel.

LinkedIn Dre



LinkedIn Profile:

SOCIAL

https://www.linkedin.com/in/miguelaurrutia/

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Global IT Director

Kaseya Miami, Florida

12/2018 – Present

- Execute strategic initiatives established by the Chief Operating Officer (COO).
- Develop and mentor a high-performing team while overseeing delivery projects and budget.
- Form a global team of associates across India, Dublin, and Miami.
- Integrate networks from acquisition into parent company while leveraging IT support team.
- Lead project manager overseeing the Office 365 Global email migration.
- Standardize telecommunications by providing a convenient hybrid solution.
- Negotiate renewals for license and maintenance agreements.

Assistant Director | IT Operations

City of Doral

Doral, Florida

12/2014 - 12/2018

- Played a pivotal role in the administration of a \$6.6M budget.
- Reduced technical and overhead expenses by \$204,000 contributing to the overall financial health of the IT department.
- Oversaw a \$200,000 budget needed to develop a security awareness training program, endpoint security, and perimeter security with Palo Alto Networks.
- Directed a team of 15 technical associates responsible for all IT related projects.
- Fashioned documentation for Invitation to Bid (ITB) reflecting technology needs and memo resolutions for City Council and Executive Leadership.
- Received a recognition award for outstanding performance while delivering results within a leadership role.

CONTACT



Miami, Florida *Location*



+1 (305) 496-3557 *Phone Number*



Miguel.A.Urrutia@outlook.com

Email

EDUCATION

Master of Science (M.S.) Security Management

Colorado Technical University 2013 – 2015

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Information Systems Security

ITT Technical Institute - Miami 2008 - 2013

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing & Switching (CCNA)

Issued by Cisco

Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)

Windows 7

Issued by Microsoft

MIGUEL A. URRUTIA GLOBAL IT DIRECTOR



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY (Continued)

Network and System Administrator | Supervisor

Ricoh Latin America Weston, Florida

03/2014 - 12/2014

- Governed a global team of 26 IT professionals from 13 countries in providing network services for Latin America.
- Effectively reduced tensions between Ricoh America and Ricoh Latin America during a merger and acquisition while exhibiting transformational leadership, strategic negotiating tactics, and conflict resolution skills.
- Implemented a \$1M global firewall resolution utilizing extensive communication and coordination between Ricoh America Security Engineers.
- Implemented Cisco switches, routers, Meraki wireless, and cable management while monitoring the network with third-party tools including SolarWinds, NetBrain, and Zenoss.
- Served as point of contact (POC) contact and interpreter for Ricoh English-speaking network and software engineers.

Business Applications Specialist

Wells Fargo

Miami, Florida

05/2012 - 03/2014

- Contributed to the development and implementation of innovative test scripts reflecting the Business Continuing plan (BCP) for application sites.
- Developed and executed an internal Microsoft Access form to maintain an inventory of company closures while providing access to business units across the network.

Computer Sales Consultant

Tiger Direct

Miami, Florida

04/2011 - 04/2012

- Exceeded minimum sales quota of \$25,000 to \$40,000 every week by increasing the rate of repeat customer purchases.
- Delivered technology pre-sales, consulting sessions for small to mid-sized businesses.
- Recommended appropriate network design, hardware, and software purchases based on organization requirements.
- Educated consumers on servers, desktop applications, laptops, routers, switches, access points, and cat5/cat5 cabling.

EXPERTISE

Project Management

Network Administration

Strategic Planning | Business Analysis

Cisco Meraki | Linux | VMware

Windows | Mac OS

Cyber-security | Help Desk Support

Palo Alto Networks

MS Excel | PowerPoint | Project

LANGUAGES

English | Spanish

2019 PROJECTS

Kaseya Global Email Migration 0365 Feb 2019 – Present

Kaseya Global Meraki Migration

Jan 2019 – Present

Kaseya Global Telecommunication Migration Jan 2019 – Present

Global Microsoft Teams Integration Jan 2019 – Mar 2019

Kaseya Global Data Center Move Jan 2019 – Feb 2019